

sophiahoffman@hotmail.com

github.com/sophiahoffman

in linkedin.com/in/sophia-hoffman

ABOUT

Previous experience as a Naval officer and finance professional has honed my attention to detail and the ability to hit the ground running. Let me implement practical solutions to your analytics and software development challenges.

SKILLS

PYTHON

REACT

GITHUB

DJANGO

SQL

HTML

POWERBI

CSS

TABLEAU

JSON

DATA

HTTP

ANALYTICS

POSTGRESQL

POWERPOINT

PUBLIC

EXCEL

SPEAKING

CA LICENSED

SOA EXAM FM/P

CPA (INACTIVE) • CFA LEVEL I

CAPSTONE PROJECT

US CITIZEN INT'L TRAVEL

How do economic factors such as unemployment, GDP, inflation and exchange rates effect the international travel patterns of US citizens? Using data from the Bureau of Labor Statistics, Federal Reserve, Bureau of Economic Analysis and National Tourism and Travel Office, I take a deep dive into what factors influence US international travelers.

https://github.com/sophiahoffman/ analytics-capstone-us-citizentravel-economy

EDUCATION

NASHVILLE SOFTWARE SCHOOL DATA ANALYTICS

NASHVILLE SOFTWARE SCHOOL FULL STACK WEB DEVELOPER

NORTHWESTERN UNIVERSITY MASTER OF SCIENCE, ANALYTICS

UNIVERSITY OF WISCONSIN, MADISON

CERTIFICATE IN ACTUARIAL SCIENCE

SAN DIEGO STATE UNIVERSITY BACHELOR OF ARTS, INTERNATIONAL BUSINESS

EXPERIENCES

NASHVILLE SOFTWARE SCHOOL ANALYTICS BOOTCAMP | MARCH 2020 - JUNE 2020

Full-time three-month bootcamp designed to develop critical data analytics and business intelligence skills through individual and group projects:

- Focus on Report Building, Storytelling, Presentation Skills, Dashboards
- Experienced in Extract, Transform, Load (ETL) process and merging disparate datasets to create data synergy and facilitate data analysis
- High proficiency in Python, SQL, Tableau, PowerBI and Excel

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER BOOTCAMP | SEPTEMBER 2019 - MARCH 2020

- Intensive full-time, six-month web development bootcamp with a heavy focus on group and individual projects to develop the skills necessary to build full-stack applications using Python/Django, Django REST API, React, react-bootstrap, bootstrap, CSS, JSON, JavaScript and HTML.
- Git/GitHub for version control and to enable group collaboration; project management tracking with Github Projects
- Hands on application of Object Oriented Programming fundamentals with a focus on developing DRY, modular, readable code and reusable components

DATA ANALYTICS CONSULTANT INTERACTIVE HEALTH | MAY 2016 - APRIL 2018

- Updated white paper detailing descriptive statistics of client companies and program participants
- Performed linear regression in **R** to determine major, actionable factors to increase program participation
- Data visualization in **Tableau** to provide aggregate reporting to clients

RETAIL ACCOUNTING MANAGER O'NEILL SURF SHOPS | FEBRUARY 2008 - MAY 2013

- Generated consolidated and by store financial statements for multimillion dollar retail enterprise - SAGE MAS 90
- Conducted detailed variance analysis of year over year and actual to budget financials
- Provided operational reports to key decision makers: buyer margin, inventory analysis, sales reports
- Completed California CPA licensure

STAFF AUDITOR

PRICEWATERHOUSECOOPERS | JANUARY 2007 - FEBRUARY 2008

- Participated in audits of publicly traded and pre-IPO companies in the technology and construction sectors
- Reviewed financial statements in SEC filings (10K,10Q) for consistency and accuracy

INTELLIGENCE OFFICER **US NAVY | OCTOBER 1997 - JULY 2005**

- Supported carrier air wing operations by giving pre-mission intelligence briefings and taking detailed post-mission debriefs as the Intelligence Officer for Fighter Squadron 213 (F-14D)
- · Developed and conducted training on operational intelligence reporting for the Naval Strike and Air Warfare Center training facility
- Prepared and conducted intelligence briefings on North Korean geopolitical activities to key US and South Korean military officials